Contact

+91-8105504394 (Mobile) karthikskmysore@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/karthik-s-krishna-iyer (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Oracle RDBMS
SQL/PLSQL
Informatica ETL Tool

Languages

Hindi

English

Kannada

Tamil

Certifications

DS C27 PGDDS LOA

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

DS C27 Prep Course PGDDS

Karthik S Krishna Iyer

Associate Project Manager at EY | Guidewire Data Management Practice | Data Science Enthusiast | PGD IIIT Bangalore

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Over 10 years of professional experience working in IT Industry. Worked for Property and Casualty (P&C) insurance clients from US and UK regions. Started career with Ernst and Young Pvt. Ltd (EY) as a developer migrating data from disparate data sources into new insurance product called Guidewire. Played various key roles as data analyst, data mapper and supporting business analyst roles both at offshore and onshore with good domain knowledge in the field of P&C Insurance. Currently serving in EY as a Senior Consultant providing end-to-end technology solutions for migrating data from various insurance legacy systems into Guidewire, building frameworks using ETL tools such as MSBI and Informatica.

Experience

EY

7 years 8 months

Associate Project Manager October 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- ★ Mostly Individual contributor for one of the largest Household and Motor Insurer in UK.
- ⋆ Data Analyst, Data Mapping proving mapping specifications for producing General Ledger reports (GL) out of GW ClaimCenter.
- ★ There were 10 reports produced covering key financial metrics Payments, Reserves, Recovery, RecoveryReserves extracted out of GW CC.
- * Help testers create sample data for validating the reports and checking if it is meeting the business requirements.
- * Awarded most valuable player and much appreciated by client.

Senior Technical Lead September 2019 - October 2021 (2 years 2 months)

- ★ Led data migration team from offshore for Claims migration with a team size of 6 for one of the UK insurers primarily playing the role of Data Analyst.
- ★ Demonstrated technical capabilities and supported client in order to get past technical and environmental issues and building trust.
- * Built a new Framework which can automate the data migration activity from legacy to Guidewire ClaimCenter using SSIS ETL tool in one click.
- * The framework do not require any manual intervention and is capable of handling most of the issues from source to target Guidewire.
- ★ Carried out Show and Tell activity to demonstrate the above Framework.
 This was well received by all key stakeholders of the project and is now being reused for future Guidewire migrations.
- * Received Onsite Recognition Award twice in the same year for having delivered the project and managing team successfully.

Technical Lead

October 2017 - September 2019 (2 years)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

As part of Practice Development project:

- * Created an accelerator which builds Operational Data Store (ODS) based on a generic Insurance Industry model.
- ⋆ Developed an asset for Volumetric Reconciliation to reconcile Guidewire ClaimCenter and ODS entities using PL/SQL
- ⋆ For a leading US based Insurer, Integrated Personal Auto, Commercial Auto and Workers compensation business lines
- ★ Data from legacy systems and Guidewire ClaimCenter transformed into an 3NF ODS for consumption by downstream applications.
- * Represented the team as Insurance Domain Expert

Associate Technical Lead

September 2015 - September 2017 (2 years 1 month)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- * Analyze the business requirements and build ETL logic to generate flat files using MSBI SSIS, SSRS.
- ⋆ Data in the form of XML payloads was generated from Guidewire ClaimCenter application and loaded into staging tables
- ★ Carried out Guidewire upgrade project for ClaimCenter from version 7 to version 9.
- * Having defined the upgrade steps, resolved issues/challenges while upgrading Guidewire ClaimCenter on merged code base.

HCL Technologies

Senior Software Engineer
July 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Played a lead role in building a reconciliation framework to reconcile claims legacy system and Guidewire ClaimCenter for one of largest workers compensation insurer in Canada

Infosys

Senior Software Engineer

November 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Mysuru, Karnataka, India

Responsible for providing production support and maintenance activities for these applications - Interwoven Teamsite and Autonomy IDOL

EY

Software Engineer

July 2010 - November 2012 (2 years 5 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Data Migration from legacy applications to Guidewire ClaimCenter for one of the top Property and Casualty insurer (P&C) in US

Education

International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore Post Graduation Diploma, Data Sceince · (2020 - 2021)

Visvesvaraya Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) from The National Institute of Engineering, Mysuru, Karnataka, India, Industrial and Production (I&P) · (2006 - 2010)